Now we're not going to test the deploying this to a test net quite yet,
我们暂时还不打算把它部署到测试网上
because well, we don't have any unit tests yet.
因为我们还没有进行任何的 Unit 测试
We need to write unit tests before we want to ever test running this on a test net.
我们要在测试网上进行测试之前编写 Unit 测试
So we have our deploy script, we have our contracts, that means it's time for us to write some tests.
现在我们有了部署脚本，还有了合约，这意味着我们该编写一些测试了
We'll come over here we'll create a new folder called test.
我们在这里创建一个新的文件夹，命名为 `test`
And for now, we'll just make our unit tests.
现在我们开始创建我们的 Unit 测试
So unit tests, and in here we create a new file called raffle.test.js.
新建一个名为 `Raffle.test.js` 的文件
And let's write some unit tests.
让我们开始编写 Unit 测试
Now for these unit tests, we are going to be a little bit verbose here,
对 Unit 测试来说，它的内容会有些冗长
we're going to make our coverage really, really good here.
我们会尽量覆盖所有方面
It's not gonna be perfect, but this is going to be pretty verbose.
可能不会特别完美，但会足够详细
So I'm gonna go pretty quickly here.
让我们快速过一遍这里
So you can feel free to pause, slow me down, speed me up whatever you need to learn this section.
你可以随时按照自己的学习需要选择暂停，放慢速度，或是加快速度
It is really good muscle memory to go through writing these tests
编写这些测试对形成肌肉记忆很有帮助
and understand what you should be thinking about when you're writing these tests.
还能让你理解编写测试时该思考哪些东西
So feel free to speed up the parts You already know and slow down the new parts.
所以请自由选择加速你已经了解的部分或是放慢不了解的新部分
Because we are going to go over some new information here.
因为我们会在这里介绍一些新的信息
writing tests may seem like a tedious process.
编写测试的过程看起来可能会比较枯燥
But I promise as you get better at writing these tests,
但我保证，随着你编写测试的熟练度不断提高
you'll realize that these are the things that you can rely on
你就会意识到，当你工程不顺，或是代码不知道怎么处理的时候
when stuff doesn't work. And when you're not sure how to code, something,
这些才是你可以依靠的东西
getting this muscle memory down, writing these tests is going to make you a fantastic engineer.
编写这些测试，获取这些肌肉记忆可以让你成为一个优秀的工程师
So let's go through and we'll write some of these verbose tests here
让我们继续，编写一些详细的测试
to try to make this really good and have this have really good coverage.
并尽量确保较高的覆盖率
And if you want to go back later on, and see if you can give it even more coverage,
如果你以后想回来，看看是否能给它更高的覆盖率
and even better tests, please feel free to do so.
甚至是更好的测试，也请随意如此
But let's get started. Let's write some tests.
让我们开始吧，来编写一些测试
So we're going to start out pretty much the same way we've been starting everything out,
我们将以与之前几乎相同的方式开始
we're going to grab our development chains,
我们会先获取我们的开发链
so that we only run our unit tests on a development chain.
这样我们就只会在开发链上运行我们的 Unit 测试了
So we'll do const development chains, equals require dot dot slash dot dot slash helper, RD, hard hat config,
首先写 `cosnt  = require("../../helper-hardhat-config")`
and then we'll say not development chains, that includes network dot name, and describe that skip.
接着写 `!developmentChains.includes(network.name) ? describe.skip`
Otherwise, we'll do describe,
否则就执行 `describe()`
(译者注："C ? T : F" 是一种名为三元条件运算符的简化 if 语句)
so this first describe is going to be our raffle unit tests.
第一个 "describe" 是我们的 `"Raffle"` Unit 测试
And this is going to be an async. function.
然后这里是一个 `async function`
So raffle unit tests so that it comes on the next line, it looks a little bit better. Alright, great.
"Raffle Unit Tests" 被放到了下一行，看起来更好看一点，非常好
Now, what are some of the main things that we're going to need to deploy?
现在，我们主要需要部署的是哪些东西
Well, we're gonna need to deploy a raffle, we're probably going to want a VRF core to a tour be to mock
嗯，我们需要部署 `raffle, vrfCoordinatorV2Mock`
graded before each, that's going to be an async function,
测试前是 `beforeEach(async function())`
where we go ahead and we get these
我们就在这里获取它们
will say const. Employer equals await, get named accounts.
我们要写 `const  = await getNamedAccounts()`
So we're gonna need to import get named accounts or require get name accounts from hard hat,
所以我们需要导入 "getNamedAccounts" 或者说从 "hardhat" 中 "require getNamedAccounts"
then we're going to want to deploy these using our fixtures.
接下来我们要用 "fixture" 部署它们
So we can say await deployments.
我们可以写 `await deployments`
And then we're going to import deployments as well from hardhat
我们同样需要从 "hardhat" 中把 "deployments" 导入进来
dot fixture, and we're going to call all,
然后是 `.fixture()` 并调用 `["all"]`
we're going to deploy everything.
表明我们要部署所有内容
And again, if we look at our one, our raffle has the alt tag,
如果我们看一下 "01" 我们的 "raffle" 具有标签 "all"
and our Oh, our mocks also have the alt tag,
再看一下 "00" 我们的 "mocks" 同样具有 "all" 标签
okay, perfect.
OK 非常完美
Once we deploy everything,
一旦我们部署了所有的内容
we can say raffle equals await ethers dot get to contract.
我们就可以执行 `raffle = await ethers.getContract`
And we got to import ethers from hard hat, like so.
同样需要把 "ethers" 从 "hardhat" 中导入进来，就像这样
And we'll say it will get the raffle contract and we'll connect it to our Deployer.
然后我们要写上 `"Raffle"` 合约，并将其连接至我们的 "deployer"
And then we're going to do the same thing with VRF coordinator v2 Mock equals await ethers dot get contract, the RF coordinator, B to MK
然后同样的操作 `vrfCoordinatorV2Mock = await ethers.getContract("VRFCoordinatorV2Mock")`
connect this to deployer as well.
并将其同样连接至 "deployer"
Alright, great, our first set of tests describe, they're going to be the constructor.
好的，下面是我们的第一组测试 `describe("constructor")`
And this is going to be an async function.
然后是 `async function`
And let's do this. Let's create an IT initial initializes the raffle correctly,
让我们开始吧，创建一个 `it("initializes the raffle correctly")`
this is going to be an async function.
还有一个 `async function()`
Now I just want to make a note, because ideally, we make our tests have just one assert, or it
现在我要提醒一下，“理想情况下，我们要让测试中的每个 "it" 都只拥有一处断言”
just keep that in mind is that ideally, we want to have just one assert for it.
只需要记住这一点，理想情况下，我们希望每个 "it" 都只有一处断言
But we're going to have a bunch because like I said, we're being a little bit loose here.
但我们会出现存在多处断言的情况，因为，我们的要求不那么严格
So we want to just make sure that our raffle is initialized correctly.
首先我们要确保抽奖会被正确地初始化
So we'll say const raffle state, and we'll get that raffle state
所以我们说 `const raffleState` 然后我们获取对应的抽奖状态
because we want to make sure that we start in an open raffle state.
因为我们要确保开始时抽奖要处于开放状态
So we'll say const, raffle state equals await raffle dot get raffle state.
所以我们说 `const raffleState = await raffle.getRaffleState()`
And then we want to say assert dot equal
然后我们写 `assert.equal`
ope and then we need to import assert from Chai.
哦，我们还需要从 "chai" 中导入 "assert"
So assert equals require Chai
也就是 ` = require("chai")`
assert dot equal raffle state.to string because again, raffle state is going to be a big number.
`assert.equal(raffleState.toString())`，因为 "raffleState" 会是一个大数
And even though a raffle state is of type raffle state,
尽管抽奖状态是一个 "RaffleState" 类型
it'll return a zero if it's open and a one if it's calculating.
如果它是 "OPEN" 就会返回 "0"，如果它是 "CALCULATING" 就会返回 "1"
So this gets transformed just into a un 256.
但它会被转换为 uint256
When we call it like this, a raffle state variable here will be a big number.
当我们像这样调用它的时候，这里的 "raffleState" 就会是大数
So we want to just to string a file.
因此我们要对它使用 "toString"
So assert dot equal raffle state DOT two string zero.
所以就是 `assert.equal(raffleState.toString(), "0")`
We'll also make sure our interval gets set correctly.
我们还要确保我们的 "interval" 也能够被正确获取
So we'll do const interval equals await raffle dot get interval.
所以我们要写 `const interval = await raffle.getInterval`
And I don't know if we have one of those
不清楚我是不是还没有这个函数
it's actually C inter ball see if we have one of those.
来看一下我们是不是有这个函数
We don't have a good interval let's go ahead and add again interval function
我们还没有 "getInterval" 让我们来添加一个 "getInterval" 函数
so we'll do function get in trouble. We have public view returns you went to six
所以我们要创建一个 `function getInterval() public view returns(uint256)`
return I underscore interval
`return i_interval`
will have good interval will say raffle dot get interval
我们有了 "getInterval" 这样就可以写 "raffle.getInterval()" 了
and will also say assert dot equal interval.to string.
然后我们接着写 `assert.equal(interval.toString())`
It should equal one Ever is in our helper config, right?
它应该等于我们在 "helper-config" 中的设定，对吧？
Because we're using the interval and helper config.
因为我们是在 "helper-config" 中提到的 "interval"
So we say interval.to string should equal.
所以我们说 `interval.toString()` 它应该等于
So we'll import that as well. Network config.
我们把它也导入进来 `networkConfig`
And we'll say the interval should equal network config. Of
然后我们说 "interval" 应该等于 `networkConfig[]`
let's also make, get our chain ID up here, chain ID,
让我们在这里把 "chainId" 也创建出来 `chainId`
say const. Chain ID equals network dot config, a chain ID,
`const chainId = network.config.chainId`
network config of the chain ID of interval.
`networkConfig[chainId]["interval"]`
Alright, cool. So let's test this so far,
好的，酷~，让我们来测试一下吧
HH test or yarn, hard hat test.
And cool looks like it passed. And we have our little gas
output here. Awesome. Let's go to our Hardhead config, just so
that it doesn't always print out at gas, but there for now. So
I'm going to copy paste the gas reporter section from our last
project, like so. And we're going to have enabled gas be
false for now. So now if we run a Hardhead test, again, we
shouldn't have that gas bid printed out, we should just see
the tests and perfect, that's what we see. And our constructor
test passes. Yay, what's next, got our constructor. And we
probably could have written more tests for the rest of these. But
let's just move on. Alright, enter raffle, that's going to be
our next describe block. So it will do describe,
enter, raffle. And this is going to be an async function. And
we'll say it reverts when you don't pay enough, right, because
one of the first things that we check is that they're paying
enough. So we want to make sure that this actually reverts if
they don't pay enough. So this will be an async function. Where
we're going to do that same expect await thing. So we're
going to import expect from Chai, which comes from those
waffle matchers. And we're gonna say await, expect raffle dot
enter a raffle. And we're not going to pass any value here,
we're going to expect it to dot b dot reverted with. And if we
look here, we want it to be reverted with this raffle not
enough eath entered. So we can put that in quotes raffle not
enough eath entered. Now we can try this out. Make sure that it
actually works. Ah ah test dash dash grep. Put this in quotes
that you don't pay enough. And awesome. We're passing there.
What else do we want to test? Well, we want to test that if
the raffle isn't open, we also revert but we'll test that in a
little bit. As we kind of test the rest of the functionality.
We want to see that it records players when they enter. So this
will be an async function. And now we'll enter the raffle.
First we're going to need that raffle entrance fee. Let's go
ahead and save that at the top. So we'll say let raffle VRF
coordinator be to mock raffle entrance fee and then our before
each will say raffle entrance fee equals a weight ethers dot
get entrance fee. This should be raffle dot get entrance fee. So
now we have this raffle entrance fee, you can use it to enter the
raffle we'll say a weight raffle dot enter raffle with a value of
raffle entrance fee. And we can make sure that our Deployer here
has been correctly recorded. So since right now we're connected
to the Deployer. We'll just make sure that that deployer actually
is in our contract. So we'll say const player from contract
equals await raffle dot get player of zero, because we
record them in our players array and we have our get players
function which pulls them out. And then we'll say assert dot
equal player, player from contract should be the Deployer.
So now we can grep for this in our hard head test. Make sure
this works. HH test dash dash grep. Deployer is not defined.
We've got it up here. But we actually didn't save it
globally. So we got to do let common Deployer. And we'll say
deployer equals await get named accounts. And we'll wrap it like
this to get the deployer Awesome. Let's try this again.
And awesome. What else should this do?